<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Reasons humbly offered to the consideration of Parliament, agaist the passing of a bill, intituled, An Act for the better preservation of the wood in Deane-Forrest, so far as it related to in inclosure of the moorish land, called Wall moore.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B28762</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99885926</idno>
  <idno type="VID">188530</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240895290</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing R550B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 816.m.16[29]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R225198</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99885926</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99885926e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B28762)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 188530)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C11:1[25])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Reasons humbly offered to the consideration of Parliament, agaist the passing of a bill, intituled, An Act for the better preservation of the wood in Deane-Forrest, so far as it related to in inclosure of the moorish land, called Wall moore.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1690]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing CD-ROM, 1996.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Forests and forestry --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Inclosures --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:188530:1"/>
            <head>Reasons humbly offered to the Consideration of Parliament, against the passing of a Bill, Intituled, <hi>An Act for the better Preservation of the Wood in</hi> DEANE-<hi>Forrest, so far as it relates to the Inclosure of the Moorish Land, called</hi> Wall<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>moore.</head>
            <p n="1">I. BEcause many of the Free-holders within the Perambulation of the said Forrest, whose Habitations are adjoyning to <hi>Wallmoore,</hi> and whose right of Common there is undeniable; as also many other Persons who time out of mind have enjoyed Common of Herbage there, will be greatly prejudi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced, and many of them who now live well, if <hi>Wallmoore</hi> be Inclosed must inevitably be ruined, and necessarily fall upon the Parishes adjacent for maintenance; which will be an insuperable burthen to the Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred of St. <hi>Brevill</hi>'s, in which there are above Forty Families (that borders upon <hi>Wallmoore,</hi> and have no other Common within four miles of them,) that will be great sufferers if the Inclosure desired should be per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted.</p>
            <p n="2">II. The Inclosing of the said Lawn is contrary to the main scope and intent of the late Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, Intituled, <hi>An Act for the Increase and Preservation of Timber within the Forrest of</hi> Deane, <hi>and for the Inclosing of</hi> 11000 <hi>Acres thereof,</hi> which expresses that such ground shall be Inclosed as is most apt and meet to produce Wood and Timber for the future benefit of the Kingdom, and may be best spared from the use of the Commoners. For, first, This Act declares this Lawn altogether unfit for the producing of Wood or Timber. And secondly, This <hi>Wallmoor</hi> cannot be spared from the use of the Commoners, without the grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>test mischief to them imaginable, sending them above five miles for Common, who have it now lying at their doors, and taking from them more in value by Inclosing this 250 Acres than the taking away of 1000 Acres in any other part of the Forrest (more proper to answer the design of the former Act) will do. Besides, there are the Free-holders and Tenants of the Manour of <hi>Rodleigh,</hi> who have undoubted right of Common in all parts of the said Forrest. And although <hi>Prima facie</hi> the Inclosure of <hi>Wallmoore</hi> seems only to concern a few borderers thereon, yet duly consider'd it will appear prejudicial to the whole Forrest for above 1000. head of Gattel, as Horses, Oxen, Cows, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> now kept upon that Moor, will be thrown upon the Forrest if <hi>Wallmoor</hi> be Inclosed.</p>
            <p n="3">III. It is conceived altogether unnecessary to enclose the said Lawn for the uses in the Bill mentioned: For that the Act for Inclosing the 11000 Acres hath in express words made Provision for defraying the Charge of making and maintaining the said Inclosures, And the Provision thereby made is sufficient for ever (if duly ordered) to raise 150 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> for the uses in this Bill mentioned. There being vast quantities of old de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cay'd Wood and Timber (no way fit for Shipping), that prudently managed and carefully cut by degrees every year, will easily raise the money desired by this Bill without doing any prejudice.</p>
            <p n="4">IIII. There is some Reason to suspect a design of some Persons to make a private advantage of this Inclo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sure desired. For that this Lawn (when Inclosed) will be worth at least double the Rent of 150 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> Intended to be reserved; besides, will raise money to Answer all the Charge of the Inclosure. And it would be very hard to take from the Country 400 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> to Answer the Charge only of 150 <hi>l. Per Ann.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Upon the whole matter, It will be somewhat severe upon the Country if after 11000 Acres of their Common is enclosed by their Consent for a National good; the same Parliament (that took Care such Inclo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sure should be with least prejudice to their Common) should now by a subsequent Act without their Consent take away the best of their Common: especially,</p>
            <p n="1">I. Because the same is not fit for Timber which was the end of enclosing the said 11000 Acres.</p>
            <p n="2">II. Because it is supposed the full 11000 Acres is already enclosed, were the enclosure measured by the Pole measure.</p>
            <p n="3">III. For that there is a way already provided for Answering the Charge of Maintaining the Inclosures.</p>
            <p n="4">IIII. If there were not such provision yet is there no necessity of Inclosing <hi>Wallmoore;</hi> for there are other Lawns within the Inclosures made (to wit) in <hi>Kannop, Wttewood</hi> and other places, on which no Timber will ever grow, which if separated would raise the 150 <hi>l. Per Ann.</hi> desired, without prejudice to any mens right of Common or the Kings Inclosures.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>